Finding Aid for the Photographers' Collection LSC.0098
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Shelflist
  - *Photographers Collection., 249 photographs. Various sizes, mounted and unmounted.
    - Monterey Bay Vicinity., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      #8 [Ranch, crop in field]
    - San Diego to Monterey., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      #1 [Detail, rocks and surf]
      #2 [View, coast and surf]
      #3 [Seagull perched on rock]
      #4 [View of lake, broken tree trunk in foreground]
      #5 "Eroded Rock," Point Lobos, 1929.
      #6 [Ranch, Japatul Valley]
      #7 [Tomato plants, near Big Sur]
    - Lake Tahoe., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      #[View of roadside with bridge and car]
      #2 [Rubicon Point, Lake Tahoe]
      #3 Lake Van Norden.
      #4 [Clouds over lake]
      #5 [Section of fallen tree]
      #6 [Emerald Bay]
      #7 [Donner Lake, crane in foreground]
    - Portraits., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 10a)
      #[Paul Jordan Smith]
      #"Lincoln Steffens."
      #"Robinson Jeffers."
    - Owens Valley., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      #1 [Eroded rock, Alabama Hills]
      #2 [Steel tower and trees]
      #3 [Sierra Nevada ranch]
      #4 Rock erosion, Point Lobos, 1930.
    - Mojave Desert., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      #1 [Eroded calcite, Colorado Desert]
      #2 [Plants and eroded rocks]
      #3 [Eroded rock]
      #4 [Joshua tree stalks]
      #5 Wonderland of rocks, Mojave D[esert]
      #6 [Surgeons tree]
      #7 [Eroded rock with vertical cliff]
      #8 [Eroded rock formation]
      #9 Rattlesnake Valley, Mojave D[esert]
      #10 [Cholla Cactus, Colorado Desert]
      #11 [Amboy crater]
    - Bodega Bay., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
      #1 [Western shore, Tomales Bay]
      #2 [Mud flats, Tomales Bay]
      #3 [Indian's Bay]
      #4 [Sonoma County Coast]
      #5 [Warning Sing, Duncan's Point]
      #6 [Cove at Duncan's Point]
    - Lake Tenaya., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 14)
      #1 [Ruined shack at Gin Flat]
      #2 Lake Tenaya.
      #3 Roots in water, Lake Tenaya.
      #4 [View from base, rock cliff]
      #5 [Twisted trees, lake in background]
      #6 [Boats, Bodega Bay]
      #7 [Detail, base of tree]
      #8 [Skeletal tree fragment]
      #9 [Mountain grade with rubble and trees]
      #10 [Eroded tree fragment and rock]
      #11 [Skeletal trees]
    - High Sierra., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 15)
      #1 [Large cloud above the Minarets]
      #2 [Detail, pine trees]
      #3 [Mono Lake, dead trees in the foreground]
      #4 [Clouds above Minarets]
      #5 [Devil's post pile]
      #6 [Iceburg Lake, tree stump in foreground]
      #7 [Deserted cabin]
    - Desert Vistas., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      #1 Red Rock Canyon.
      #2 Rainbow over Borego.
      #3 Cloud over Panamints.
      #4 [Flowering Taper]
      #5 Rattlesnake Valley, Mojave D[esert].
      #6 Palm Cañon, Borego.
    - Seeing California with Edward Weston., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
      #1 [Disc shapped calcite]
      #2 [Eroded sandstone]
      #4 [Four Agave stalks]
      #5 [Small eroded rock]
      #6 [Agave stalks, Colorado Desert]
    - Miscellaneous., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      #1 [Detail, base of Devil's Post Pile]
      #2 "Perry Newberry."
      #3 [Barrel cacti, Colorado Desert]
      #4 Kelp.
      #5 [Mount Ritter and Banner Peak]
      #6 [Minarets with clouds]
    - Redwood Highway., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      #1 [California Buckeye, near Lake Tahoe]
      #2 [Grassy hillside with oaks]
      #3 [Fenced grass hillside]
      #4 [Small river through mountain basin]
      #5 [Driftwood and barn, Crescent city]
      #6 [Ferns growing in uprooted tree]
      #7 [Detail, decaying tree and ferns]
      #8 [Ferns and redwoods]
      #9 [Section of fallen redwood and ferns]
      #10 [Four burned tree turnks]
      #11 [View, rolling hills]
      #12 [Burned trees, overlooking ocean]
    - Northern Coast., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
      #1 [Child's grave]
      #2 [Alder Creek]
      #3 [San Francisco piers]
      #4 [Tomales Bay mudflats]
      #5 [Mudflats]
      #6 [Cypress and ocean, Point Lobos]
      #7 [Albion]
      #8 [Rock in surf]
      #9 [Coast, south of Fort Brag]
      #10 [Coast and hills, highway in foreground]
      #11 [Foam on beach, Duncan's Point]
    - Miscellaneous., Unmounted prints, 20 x 25cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
      #1 Dunes, Oceano.
      #2 [Eroded rocks, ocean in background, Point Lobos]
      #3 Dunes, Oceano, 1936; wind erosion.
      #4 Cement worker's glove, 1936.
      #5 Wind erosion; Dunes, Oceano.
      #6 Wind erosion; Dunes at Oceano.
      #7 [Beach at sunset]
      #8 [Almond orchard near Clear Lake]
      #9 [Haystacks]
      #10 [Cloud]
    - Mounted and overmatted prints., (photographs chiefly 20 x 25cm.) (Box 3)
      #5 Dead sea gull, northern coast, 1937.
      #15 Kelp washed ashore, 1930.
      #21 Untitled [nude], 1938.
      #27 Point Lobos, California, near Monterey, 1930.
      #32 Clouds, 1936.
      #34 Death Valley, 1939.
      #39 Impounded water, Coolidge Dam, Arizona, 1938.
      #40 Ubahebe Crater, Death Valley, 1938.
      #41 Untitled [wall and ceiling], undated.
      #42 Untitled [ranch], undated.
      #43 Untitled [impressions in sand], 1937.
      #44 Convent from Point Lobos, 1938.
      [Madeleine Ruthven]
    - Mounted and overmatted prints., (photographs chiefly 20 x 25cm.) (Box 4)
      #4 Death Valley, 1939.
      #13 Untitled [vegetable], 1933.
      #16 Pepper, 1929.
      #17 Untitled [courtyard] 1926.
      #18 Untitled [nude] 1923.
      #38 Cats and Juguetes, 1944.
      #45 Lake Van Norden, 1937.
      #49 Untitled [rocks with vegetation] 1944.
      #55 Sand dunes; Death valley, 1938.
      #-- Death Valley. Clouds over Panamint Range.
    - Mounted and overmatted prints., (photographs chiefly 20 x 25cm.) (Box 5)
      #1 John Cowper Powys, 1918.
      #3 Untitled portrait, 1940.
      #8 [Eroded rocks] undated.
      #9 Untitled [ranch] 1941.
      #12 Rock; Point Lobos, 1935.
      #14 Diego and Frieda Rivera, 1930.
      #20 Untitled [trees] 1937.
      #24 San Francisco Bay from Sausalito, 1939.
      #25 Tide pool; Point Lobos, 1945.
      #26 Monterey cypress, undated.
      #31 Point Lobos, 1942.
      #33 Untitled [cypress] 1950.
      #-- Robinson, William Wilcox, 1929.
      #46 Cypress; Point Lobos, 1930.
      #56 Panamints, Death Valley, 1938.
    - Mounted and overmatted prints., (photographs chiefly 20 x 25cm.) (Box 6)
      #2 Untitled [nude] 1927.
      #10 Metro=Goldwyn-Mayer, ghost set, 1939.
      #11 Dunes, 1936.
      #19 Untitled [kelp] 1932.
      #22 Untitled [cypress and ocean] undated.
      #23 Eroded rock; Point Lobos, 1930.
      #30 Tenaya lake, Granite Cliff, 1937.
      #35 Rock erosion, Point Lobos, 1930.
      #36 Potato cellar, Tahoe, 1937.
      #37 Untitled [cabin] undated.
      #47 Peppers, 1929.
      #48 Corral, 1935.
      #50 Death Valley, 1937.
      #51 Untitled [jawbones] 1940.
    - Unmounted photographs.
      - Paul Jordan Smith and John Cowper Powys, 1918; [copy photograph]
      - Powell, George Harold, 1921; (2 copies)
      - Wilbur Jordan Smith and his brother, Ralph, ca. 1919
      - No. 2. "Bathing Pool" (Wilbur Jordan Smith and Ralph W. Smith), ca. 1919
    - #a Mina Copper, hands on hips, 1929 (Box 1)
    - #b Mina Copper, face in hands, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Photographers Collection., 2 photographs. (Box 4)
    1. Derelect wooden house.
    2. Portrait of Frank Lloyd Wright.
  - Photographers Collection., 2 items. (Box 104)
  - Photographers Collection., 3 items. Photographs. (Box 105)
  - *Views in the national parks. v.p., ca. 1927-1928.; 12 items. 40 x 68 cm. Original photographs. (Box 5)
  - *** [Women are beautiful] New York (N.Y.), DEP Editions, [ca.1981]; 1 item. 42.5 x 54.3 cm. Portfolio of photographs.
    15 black and white images 27.8 x 35.2 cm., mounted and overmatted 40.5 x 50.8 cm.
    Portfolio #II.
    - New York City, New York, 1969
      Pregnant woman hailing a cab.
    - Beverly Hills, California, 1980
      Girls with bicycles.
    - Venice, California, 1979
      Man with bare back talking to old woman.
    - Beverly Hills, California, 1979
      Mother and daughter at restaurant.
    - Santa Monica, California, 1978
      Dancing outdoors.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1979
      Women in hats at street corner.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1980
      Women strolling with arms around each other.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1980
      Two women greet a third.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1980
      Woman with clasped hands.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1978
      Blonde woman striding.
    - Bevery Hills, California, 1978
      Girl in white skirt and tennis shoes.
    - Hutchinson, Kansas, 1976
      Amusement park meeting.
    - Venice, California, 1979
      Woman in bikini with broken wrist.
    - Houston, Texas, 1977
      Cheerleaders.
    - Beverly Hills, California, 1979
      Women outside glass windows.
  - Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs. (Box 106)
  - Photographers Collection., 13 photographs. (Box 1)
  - Garden views photographed by Florence Yoch, Lucile Council, and William Clarke. v.p., 1924-1933; 104 items. Autochrome slides.
    41 8.2 x 10 cm. slides by Williame Clarke. 63 6.5 x 9 cm. slides by Florence Yoch and Lucile Council. Views of gardens in Los Angeles, Mexico, England, France, and Italy. Florence Yoch was a Los Angeles landscape architect.
    A set of kodachrome copy slides available.
    Copy slides of all images are available for use.
    - Gates - Pool Garden, 1930; C56
    - A.P. Johnson Patio, 1933; C49
    - Charnley Parterre, 1932; C29
    - Council - General, 1930; C15
    - Burton on the Water, undated; C11
    - Villa Incontri - Pietra - Florence, 1928; B91
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 1928; B85
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 1928; B86
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 1928; B84
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 1928; B82
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 192[8]; B81
    - Villa degli Angeli - Fiesole, 1928; B80
    - Villa Colonna - Rome, 1928; B79
    - Villa Cimbroni - Rarello, 1928; B77
    - Villa Caprarola - Ronciliogne, 1928; B76
    - Aloe vera plant and tree with house in background, undated; B106
    - Villa Bel Riposo - Florence, 1928; B65
    - Villa Bel Riposo - Florence, 1928; B64
    - Villa Bel Riposo - Florence, 1928; B63
    - Villa Bel Riposo - Florence, 1928; B62
    - Tours, 1928; B53
    - Inn - Wm., Conqueror, 1928; B45
    - Chateau Vaux le Viconle, 1928; B43
    - Chateau Vaux le Viconle, 1928; B39
    - Chateau La Courance, 1928; B38
    - Chateau La Courance, 19[28?]; B37
    - Chateau La Courance, Mme. Ganay?, 1928; B36
    - St. Catharine's Court, 1928; B28
    - Shipton court - house, 1928; B24
    - Shipton court - pool, 192[8]?; B23
    - Shipton court - border, 19[28]?; B26
    - Mill Hay - Snow Hill, near Broadway, Mrs. Stuart Drury, 1928; B19
    - Lygon Arms - Broadway, 1928; B18
    - New House - Stratford on Avon, 1928; B21
    - Great Chalfield, undated; B13
    - Brimplon Manor, 1928; B10
    - Bibury, 1928; B8
    - Bibury, 1928; B6
    - Barrington Court, 1928; B4
    - Athelhampton, 1928; B1
    - Mitla temple, undated; A36
    - Xochimilco, undated; A30
    - Nuttall Teahouse Ext., undated; A29
    - Nuttall Teahouse Inter., undated; A28
    - Nuttall Teahouse Compl., undated; A27
    - Nuttall Entrada, undated; A24
    - Church San Angel Patio, undated; A20
    - San Angel Domes Ch., undated; A18
    - Villasenor Guadalajara, undated; A6
    - Riebeling Guadalajara, undated; A5
    - Riebeling House Guad., undated; A4
    - Riebeling House Guad., undated; A3
    - Wild Flowers, 1927; 48
    - Spain, undated; 20
    - Taromina, undated; 12
    - Garden, undated; 4
    - Garden with statues, undated; 11
    - House and garden, undated; 3
    - Laicewlas Estate - Woolbedding Surrey, England, 1924; B16
    - Basket, 45, undated; D1
    - Basket 46, undated; D2
    - Ramona's Marriage Place - Wall, undated; D16
    - Ramona's Marriage Place - Patio, undated; D18
    - Smith - Flower Walk Detail, undated; C86
    - Steward Medici Bowl, undated; C95
    - Smith - Iris & Tulips, undated; C90
    - G.P. Griffith Bird Bath, Mr. Clarke, 1931; C62
    - Schultz - Iris & Tulip, close, undated; C84
    - Schultz - Spring Walk, Detail, undated; C82
    - Hoffman - Spanish Garden, undated; C70
    - Fry - Summer Garden, 1927; C38
    - G.P. Griffith - Summer House, Mr. Clarke, 1931; C60
    - Gates Border - Orange & Yellow Section, undated; C52
    - Gates Border - Blue & Pink Section, undated; C51
    - Fry - Delphinium, 1927; C37
    - Davenport - Peach Tree, undated; C35
    - Council- Tritoma, undated; C10
    - Council - General, 1927; C6
    - Villa Medici - Florence, 1924; B94
    - Villa Medici - Florence, 1924; B93
    - Villa Medici - Florence, 1924; B92
    - Villa Gamberaia - Florence, 1924; B90
    - Villa Gamberaia - Florence, 1924; B89
    - Villa Gamberaia - Florence, 1924; B88
    - Villa Gamberaia - Florence, 1924; B87
    - Villa San Casciano - Florence, Sig. Antinori, 1924; B
    - Villa San Casciano - Florence, Sig. Antinori, 1924; B74
    - Villa San Casciano - Florence, Sig. Antinori, 1924; B73
    - Villa San Casciano - Florence, Sig. Antinori, 1924; B72
    - Villa San Casciano - Florence, Sig. Antinori, 1924; B71
    - Villa Bel Riposo - San Domenico - Florence, St. Gemme Smith, 1924; B70
    - Villa Bel Riposo - San Domenico - Florence, St. Gemme Smith, 1924; B66
    - Monastery of St. Francis - Fiesole - Florence, 1924; B57
    - Sturgis Pool, 1930; C118
    - Sturgis Pool, 1929; C115
    - Sturgis - Border, 1929; C111
    - Sturgis - Border Detail, 19[30?]; C109
    - Sturgis - Border Detail, 1929; C108
    - Pitcairn - pool, 1930; C78
    - Hotchkiss - Pool, 1930; C73
    - Hodges - Rose Garden, 1930; C67
    - Hodges - Rose Garden, 1930; C66
    - Griffith Rear Garden, 193[0?] August 17; C58
    - Villa Colonna - Rome, 1928; B78
  - *Photographers Collection., 4 items. Photographs.
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photograph. (Box 107)
  - Photographers Collection., 14 items. Photographs.
    22 items - box 38.
- Accession LSC-9999-012 backlog material, LSC-9999-012 (Box 132)